# **TONY FERGUSON**

E-mail: tonyjuniorferguson@gmail.com

A 21-year-old post-graduate, with a passion for games. After programming since the age of 12, the creation of large-scale game mods, and the finished development of a fully released video game. Also pertains knowledge of web development and database management.

Hobbies & interests include competitive gaming, swimming, PC hardware building & hanging out with friends.

### **SKILLS**

**Languages:** C++, C#, Lua, JavaScript, Python, TypeScript.

Technologies: Unreal Engine, Unity, SQL, Linux Administration, Kubernetes, Node.js, Git Version Control,

Docker.

IDEs: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code (VS Code), IntelliJ, WebStorm, DataGrip.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Creator – Element** (https://devultj.itch.io/element)

- First-person shooter game developed in Unity by a team of five university students.
- Learned about industry-standard multiplayer networking protocols.
- Utilized server authoritative network design principles.
- Learned about deferred rendering optimization techniques utilizing Unity's High-Definition Render Pipeline.
- Learned about strong user experiences & designing pleasing user interfaces.
- **Skills used**: Unity, C#.

## Project Lead, Programmer - Monolith RP

- Utilized first-party web APIs to increase security and provide speed to a game mod with up to 128 concurrent players.
- Prioritized optimization techniques and rendering optimization to provide a smooth game play experience.
- Gained knowledge of Linux based distributions to set up micro-services for game integration.
- Worked with a variety of programmers and involved in the recruitment process of new programmers.
- Skills used: Lua, SOL, Linux Administration.

#### **EXPERIENCE**



## **Lucid Games Ltd**

## August 2019 - now

An independent studio developing cutting edge games & apps. Lucid has set itself out to be a team with big ideas and the skills to deliver them.

### Junior Programmer

- Tasked with character, gameplay, networking & user-interface development.
- Website: https://lucidgames.co.uk



# **Thriving Ventures AB**

# **April 2017 – August 2019**

A group of passionate people situated around the world. They love experimenting with new ideas and technologies and like to have a bit of fun with their projects.

Programmer

- Tasked with management and programming for game projects & managing a team of over 10 people situated across the world.
- Website: <a href="https://thriving.ventures/">https://thriving.ventures/</a>

## **EDUCATION**

**BSc** University of Bolton, Games Programming

Graduated with Second Class Degree, First Division

2017 - 2019